<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Brandon Kearns]]></title><description><![CDATA[brandonkearns.com - learn, earn, sojourn. repeat.]]></description><link>https://www.brandonkearns.com</link><image><url>https://www.brandonkearns.com/logos/logo-512.png</url><title>Brandon Kearns</title><link>https://www.brandonkearns.com</link></image><generator>GatsbyJS Material Starter</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 16:06:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brandonkearns.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><author><![CDATA[Brandon Kearns]]></author><copyright><![CDATA[Copyright © 2018. Brandon Kearns]]></copyright><item><title><![CDATA[RailsBridge]]></title><description><![CDATA[It had been a long time since I had done any Rails in my career. My friend,  Raven , one of the organizers of RailsBridge Atlanta, asked me…]]></description><link>https://www.brandonkearns.com/rails-bridge</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brandonkearns.com/rails-bridge</guid><category><![CDATA[code]]></category><category><![CDATA[workshop]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Brandon Kearns]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It had been a long time since I had done any Rails in my career. My friend, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_raven_io&quot;&gt;Raven&lt;/a&gt;, one of the organizers of RailsBridge Atlanta, asked me if I’d be willing to be a coach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, I said yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am quite passionate about helping to fix the PR issue that the tech industry has. It presents itself as a profession (or, pastime) that is suited to a particular type of person. And when I say type of person, I am not talking about the equally troubling race and gender disproportionality in tech - this is a problem in its own right. I am talking about the “good at math” myth or the “is he or she a technical person?” question. What even is a technical person? Technically, I am a person. But I don’t know that I am a technical person. If you must label me, I would say I am a spiritual person but stop trying to label me, anyway. I’m just Brandon. And I am interested in technology enough to persevere through obstacles that I run into long enough to quench the curiosity that started me down this path in the first place. This industry will not change if it continues to perpetuate the idea that some people just are not cut out for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I see it, curiosity and perseverance seem to be among the biggest boons to whatever success I have had in tech thus far. It is difficult to persevere without support. And this is why I was so excited to be a coach at the second RailsGirls Atlanta RailsBridge session. Initially, I was concerned that my Rails knowledge might have escaped me but then I thought about the more important bit: the students do not need me to know everything - they need support and affirmation that despite, perhaps, running into some technical difficulties, this is an industry in which they can succeed if they so choose. I cannot speak highly enough of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.railsbridge.org/about&quot;&gt;RailsBridge&lt;/a&gt; philosophy and of &lt;a href=&quot;http://railsgirls.com/atl&quot;&gt;RailsGirls&lt;/a&gt; Atlanta. This was my first time attending an event held by either organization. The day started with a wonderful breakfast before we got into the curriculum. The goal was to get the students to create their first web app - a feeling that I still remember. It was quite inspiring to see, over the course of a day, the progression of someone’s knowledge. Something that I think is taken for granted in learning a completely new skill is the starting point and everything it took to get there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know how they say showing up is a large percentage of getting something done? That’s so true. It’s also the easiest part. So, any steps taken after that are huge victories compared the alternative of still wishing you had done it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&apos;s a picture of some women who no longer have to wish they had gotten it done:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/railsbridge.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Chia Seed]]></title><description><![CDATA[What can we learn from the chia seed? Tiny & dense. Rarely thought of but rich with nutrients. When submerged in liquid, the chia seed takes…]]></description><link>https://www.brandonkearns.com/chia-seed</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brandonkearns.com/chia-seed</guid><category><![CDATA[writing]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Brandon Kearns]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;What can we learn from the chia seed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiny &amp;#x26; dense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rarely thought of but rich with nutrients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When submerged in liquid, the chia seed takes on its surroundings gracefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than losing itself it embraces its surroundings bringing itself closer to the seeds around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The seeds coalesce and create a gel that binds them together almost as if they are depending on one another in order to endure this foreign environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can we learn?&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Be That Person]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today, is the day that we take time to honor the legacy and contributions of the Rev. Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Perhaps, you had a day off…]]></description><link>https://www.brandonkearns.com/be-that-person</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brandonkearns.com/be-that-person</guid><category><![CDATA[writing]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Brandon Kearns]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today, is the day that we take time to honor the legacy and contributions of the Rev. Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Perhaps, you had a day off from work (I did not) or did not attend class today. In any case, your world is better than it would have been without the vision, struggle and teachings of MLK and the millions of fellow freedom fighters the world over. I can think of no better way to honor that work than to continue it. To suggest that we have fully overcome the structure that was put in place is to concede to that very structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We still have work to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may think, as I often do, that there is simply too much to be done for one person to go against the heavily weathered grain. There are opportunites everywhere, though. Microaggressions are real. You have either experienced or committed them. And as the social climate facilitates more self-expression we have to think about intersectionality and how it plays into the struggle. This is a lot, to be sure. And it only scratches the surface but change is never easy. It is up to us to have the courage to call to attention the behavior of our often well-intentioned friends, relatives, colleagues and, yes, ourselves. None of us is beyond reproach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of us balk at the idea of standing - often alone - on the side of progress when there is strong short-term incentive to uplift the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I don&apos;t want to be that person,&quot; you tell your friend over coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What person do you want to be, then? Because that person you don&apos;t want to be is exactly who we need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please, be that person.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Coding a New Chapter]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today was the second day of a web development course that I decided to take a little over 1 month ago. The significant people in my life…]]></description><link>https://www.brandonkearns.com/coding-a-new-chapter</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brandonkearns.com/coding-a-new-chapter</guid><category><![CDATA[coding]]></category><category><![CDATA[career]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Brandon Kearns]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div&gt;
          &lt;div
            class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot;
            style=&quot;padding-bottom: 56.25%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&quot;
          &gt;
            &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/H14bBuluwB8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen style=&quot;
            position: absolute;
            top: 0;
            left: 0;
            width: 100%;
            height: 100%;
          &quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was the second day of a web development course that I decided to take a little over 1 month ago. The significant people in my life, while excited for me, are definitely curious about my motivations for wanting to dive into web development as a career. For some of them, this curiosity is a result of their unfamiliarity with the tech industry. Okay. Others, however, seem to be inquiring about an esoteric inclination that I must have towards this type of work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Do you have any experience in tech?,” they ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What do you plan on doing with that?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graduating with a political science degree, I thought, had given me plenty of practice in finding an answer to that question. I was surprised, though, to find how comfortable I was with not having an answer. One of the changes that I have decided to implement in my life is devoting my present energies on present entities. And, I think that is what drew me to web development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had tried to teach myself before but I found that I was easily discouraged because I was accustomed to a learning pattern that was not effective for a process as dynamic as web development. Not being able to get it was not something I could deal with at the time. As it turns out not getting it is a prerequisite to getting it – and, I didn’t get that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enduring the transition from not knowing what something is to being able to implement it as you see fit is trying, but very much worth the effort. This transition is what Angela Lee Duckworth is referring to when she talks of grit being a better indicator of success than talent or IQ. The idea is really liberating after a brief reflection; at each moment, we have myriad options as to how we can allocate our energies or vital resources. And – more often than we realize – our future depends on which options we choose or decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If precedent is any indicator, the sun will rise tomorrow. By then, we each will have had countless opportunities to shape our lives in a way that is meaningful. I will take this present opportunity to thank you for reading.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[One Year in Tech]]></title><description><![CDATA[One year ago, I enrolled in a web development immersive course at  General Assembly . I can say that making this career shift was among the…]]></description><link>https://www.brandonkearns.com/one-year-in-tech</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brandonkearns.com/one-year-in-tech</guid><category><![CDATA[journey]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Brandon Kearns]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;One year ago, I enrolled in a web development immersive course at &lt;a href=&quot;https://generalassemb.ly/education/web-development-immersive&quot;&gt;General Assembly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can say that making this career shift was among the better decisions I have made in my life. And, the list of people to whom I owe a debt of gratitude is quite long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, though, I want to reflect on my experience in the tech industry and some reasons I&apos;m grateful to be a part of it. Often, it&apos;s easy to get overwhelmed by the heavy attention to detail that being in tech requires and even easier to forget how fortunate we are to be on this journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;cross-disciplinary-opportunities&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cross-disciplinary-opportunities&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Cross disciplinary opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This industry is unique in that it does not operate independently of the rest of society. That is, in virtually every sector of our world, tech has had/is making/will soon make a major impact. To that end, I have been able to do some things that I, otherwise, probably would not have been able to do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;meet people that do some very cool things and have access to very large amounts of money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;give a presentation at a Fortune 30 company about Node.js&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;meet with City Hall officials about building an app for the Atlanta Streetcar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;many more to come...!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granted, the third initiative on that list did not pan out but that&apos;s part of the game. In fact, it leads me to the next thing I&apos;m grateful for...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;failure-is-okay&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#failure-is-okay&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Failure is okay.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of things fail in tech. Every day. It can be as small as a bug in production code to an entire start-up going under. Knowing this is very helpful to think about whenever I find that I am telling myself negative stories about my worthiness as a technologist. I am glad that there has been a recent movement to embrace failure as a function of learning and growth. It truly is inevitable and actually a great thing if you can learn from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson could not have come at a better time for me and I think it is something that I learned as a direct result of being in the tech industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;being-nice-matters&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#being-nice-matters&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Being nice matters!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember going to my first meet-up and being &lt;del&gt;a little turned off&lt;/del&gt; disgusted by how smug one particular brogrammer was about my having just gotten into the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having picked up on his vibe (and likely in an attempt to let homeboy save face) one of my instructors asked him, &quot;So do you have any advice for these guys just getting into the industry?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I mean, I&apos;ve been programming since I was 10, so,&quot; Neckbeard replied, &quot;I don&apos;t really know what to tell you.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh, nice! Let me just rollback to 1998 really quick - I&apos;m sure you coded a sick RubyGem for time travel by the time you got your learner&apos;s permit&lt;/em&gt;, I thought to myself. Honestly, though, I was fairly discouraged as this was my very first meet-up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I am pointing out this exchange is because this dude has been the rare exception to my overall positive experience in the tech industry. For someone changing careers, it is important to be surrounded by encouraging voices and people secure enough to not be threatened by new faces eager to affect positive change in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don&apos;t get caught being smug to a newbie.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could absolutely go on about why I love being a part of the tech industry but I&apos;d like to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;This gratitude comes with the full realization that the industry as a whole has much work to do in many regards - especially around deliberate inclusivity and diversity. This theme will come up over and over again but I wanted to take a minute to appreciate.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>